[ water trickling ]
[ gasping and coughing ]
Help ! Someone help me !
Is someone there ?
Hey !
Oh , shit . I 'm probably dead .
- [ man ] You 're not dead . - Who 's that ?
Who 's that ?
[ man ] There 's no point in yelling . I already tried that .
Turn on the lights !
[ man ] I would if I could .
What the fuck is going on ? Where am I ?
[ man ] I don 't know yet .
What is that smell ?
[ man ] Shh . Hang on a second . I think I found something .
[ groaning ]
Holy shit .
[ vomiting ]
Aah ! Help !
Help !
[ panting ]
No one can hear you .
What the fuck is this ?
Calm down . Just-just calm down .
[ breathing heavily ]
Are you hurt ?
I don 't know . Yeah !
What 's your name ?
My name is very fucking confused .
What 's your name ? What 's going on here ?
My name is Lawrence Gordon . I 'm a doctor .
I just woke up here , just like you .
[ grunting ]
Aah !
[ Lawrence ] Recognize him ?
No .
Well , do you have any idea how you got here ?
What 's the last thing you remember ?
Nothing . I went to bed in my shithole apartment
and woke up in an actual shithole .
What about you , huh ?
There 's . .. there 's not much to tell .
I was on my way home from work , and , uh , I don 't remember anything else .
First dead body I 've ever seen .
Look different in real life .
They don 't move .
From the looks of these chains ,
someone didn 't want us to go very far , either .
[ gasps , grunts ]
Do you see any scars ?
- What ? - Huh ?
This is what they do , man ! They kidnap you and drug you .
Before you know it , you 're lying in a bathtub ,
and your kidneys are on eBay .
No one has taken your kidneys .
How can you tell from way over there ?
Because you 'd either be in terrible agony
or you 'd be dead by now . Trust me .
- What are you , a surgeon ? - Yeah .
So ...
you gonna tell me your name or what ?
Adam .
Well , Adam ...
What we need to do ...
is start thinking about why we 're here .
Whoever brought us here could have killed us by now , but they didn 't .
They must want something from us .
The question is what .
- That clock . - What about it ?
It 's brand-new .
So ?
So ... somebody obviously wanted us to know the time .
Wait . I think I might be able to reach the door .
[ grunting ]
What is that ?
Excuse me .
It 's a tape .
- Well , where 'd you find it ? - It was in my pocket .
It says , " Play me . "
[ grunting ]
Come on . Come on .
Throw it over here .
Huh ?
[ key rattles ]
[ grunts ]
No ?
[ key rattles ]
[ grunting ]
Use your shirt .
- What ? - Your shirt .
[ grunts ] Come on .
It won 't work .
Well , look around . There - - there must be something else you can use .
There 's nothing .
Well , there must be something .
Come on . You can do it .
Come on . Come on .
Again .
[ sinister voice ] Rise and shine , Adam .
You 're probably wondering where you are .
I 'll tell you where you might be .
You might be in the room that you die in .
Up until now , you 've simply sat in the shadows ,
watching others live out their lives .
But what do voyeurs see when they look into the mirror ?
Now , I see you as a strange mix of someone angry yet apathetic ,
but mostly just pathetic .
So , are you going to watch yourself die today , Adam ,
or do something about it ?
I don 't get it .
[ tape deck pops open ]
Throw me the player .
No .
You throw me your tape .
Look , we 're gonna have to work together if we want to get out of here .
Now just throw it to me .
I 'm not gonna risk breaking it .
You throw me your tape .
[ winces ]
[ sinister voice ] Dr. Gordon ...
this is your wake-up call .
Every day of your working life ,
you have given people the news that they 're going to die soon .
Now you will be the cause of death .
Your aim in this game is to kill Adam .
You have until 6 : 00 on the clock to do it .
There 's a man in the room with you .
When there 's that much poison in your blood ,
the only thing left to do is shoot yourself .
[ coughing ]
There are ways to win this hidden all around you .
Just remember , " X " marks the spot for the treasure .
If you do not kill Adam by 6 : 00 ,
then Alison and Diana will die , Dr. Gordon ...
and I 'll leave you in this room to rot .
Let the game begin .
[ tape clicks ]
Give me that .
Now .
[ tape rewinding ]
[ tape clicks ]
[ sinister voice ] Then Alison and Diana Will die , Dr. Gordon ...
and I 'll leave you in this room to rot .
Any idea who that is ?
[ sinister voice ] Let the game begin .
- He knows us . - Wait a minute .
[ tape rewinding ]
[ Adam ] What do you think ?
- Probably a joke , right ? - Shh ! Shh !
[ sinister voice ] Let the game begin .
Listen . Listen .
[ sinister voice ] Follow your heart .
[ static ]
[ tape clicks ]
[ Adam ] What the hell does " follow your heart " mean ?
There , right next to you , on the toilet .
Come on . Come on .
Oh , man .
[ groaning ]
[ spits ]
Anything ?
No solids .
Take off the lid .
Come on .
I really wish I had checked in there first .
[ chuckles ]
What is it ?
Hey .
Mind passing me the other one ?
Fuck . Fuck !
Fuck !
He doesn 't want us to cut through our chains .
He wants us to cut through our feet .
I think I may know who 's done this to us .
What did you say ?
Well , it 's - - it 's not someone I know personally .
It 's ... just someone I know of .
Jesus Christ . Tell me . Who is it ?
Last I heard ...
police still hadn 't caught him .
And the only reason I know that is because I was a suspect .
I 'll start from the beginning .
[ flies buzzing ]
This one 's not fresh anymore .
At least three weeks out .
Victim 's a 46-year-old male .
[ camera clicking ]
Died of massive blood loss , mostly through the femoral artery .
He started at the back of the cage
and tunneled his way through that razor wire so fast
it 's amazing he got as far as he did .
Cut himself so deep , we found traces of stomach acid on the floor .
We also found this .
[ click ]
[ sinister voice ] Hello , Paul . You are a perfectly healthy ,
sane , middle-class male ,
yet last month , you ran a straight razor across your wrist .
Did you out yourself because you truly wanted to die ,
or did you just want some attention ?
Tonight , you 'll show me .
The irony is that if you want to die , you just have to stay where you are ,
but if you want to live , you 'll have to out yourself again .
Find a path through the razor wire to the door .
But hurry , At 3 : 00 , that door will lock ,
and then this room becomes your tomb .
How much blood will you shed to stay alive , Paul ?
[ screaming ]
Door was on a timer .
It was unlocked until 3 : 00 .
Then it slammed shut .
He was given two hours .
[ screaming ]
[ door slams ]
[ man ] A jigsaw piece .
[ camera clicking ]
I think we 're gonna be here for a while , Sing .
[ Lawrence ] The newspapers started calling him
the Jigsaw Killer .
Actually , technically speaking , he 's not really a murderer .
He never killed anyone .
He finds ways for his victims to kill themselves .
[ camera clicking ]
[ sinister voice ] Hello , Mark .
If you 're so sick , then why do I have so many photos of you up and about ?
Let 's put your so-called illness to the test .
Right now , there 's a slow-acting poison in your veins .
The antidote is inside the safe .
Help !
[ sinister voice ] The combination to the safe ...
is written on the wall .
Hurry up and program it in , but watch your step .
And by the way , that 's a flammable substance
smeared on your body .
So I would be careful with that candle , if I were you .
Help !
Or all the people you 've burned with your act
just might have their revenge .
I found something else .
Well , uh , two things , actually .
There was someone standing outside here , watching through this peephole .
Looks like our friend Jigsaw likes to book himself
front-row seats to his own sick little games .
He was there at the last one as well .
Only this time ... he left us his penlight .
Hmm ...
Get a rush on the prints .
Copy that .
OK , this patient has an inoperable frontal-lobe tumor
extending across the midline .
It started as colon cancer .
Patient has come in for a standard checkup ,
by which we are able to monitor the rate at which his condition is declining .
The patient had - -
His name is John ...
Dr. Gordon .
He 's a very interesting person .
Thank you for that information , Zep .
As you can see , our orderlies form very special bonds with the patients .
Continuing on , the patient had - -
[ woman on speaker ] Dr. Lawrence Gordon , please page the operator .
Obviously , someone doesn 't want me to tell you what the patient had .
Excuse me .
[ door opens ]
Dr. Gordon . I 'm Detective Tapp .
This is Detective Sing . City Homicide .
Very impressive .
- Oh , thank you . - [ Tapp chuckles ]
I do my best .
Sorry to interrupt you while you 're working .
It 's fine . Now , how can I help you gentlemen ?
Are you able to tell us where you were between the hours
of 11 : 00 pm. and 1 : 00 am . last night , Doctor ?
Why is it that you 're interested ?
We 'd like to ask you a few questions about it .
For your sake , I think it 's best if we do it down at the station .
Would you like to follow us there ?
[ scoffs ]
I 'm afraid that 's-that 's quite out of the question .
I can 't just leave . I have work to do , and - -
Plus , my wife has the car today , so - -
That 's OK . You can ride with us ...
Doc .
[ chuckles ] I 'm sorry .
You 'll have to tell me again . What is this all about ?
Is this yours , Doctor ?
[ man ] So , you have no idea how your penlight
showed up at the murder scene ?
Of course not , Brett .
Well , I have to ask ...
what were you doing last night ?
I was seeing someone .
Who ?
Look , if you can 't be honest with me - -
I was visiting someone . It wasn 't a patient .
All right ?
What am I gonna do ?
Well , as your lawyer and your friend ,
my advice to you is to bite the bullet and give them your alibi now ,
' cause no one 's gonna believe you later .
[ sighs ]
That was five months ago .
He tried to set me up for murder .
OK .
We checked your alibi . It holds up .
Good . Can I go home now ?
[ Sing ] We have one of the victims who managed to escape .
We want to know if you wouldn 't mind sticking around
and listening to her testimony .
Maybe it 'll trigger something .
- I 'd like to help , really , but - - - Well , we 'd really appreciate it .
- She 's the only one who made it . - OK .
Amanda ...
in your own time ...
tell me the first thing you remember .
[ Amanda ] I woke up . All I could taste was blood ...
[ straining ]
And metal .
[ sinister voice ] Hello , Amanda .
You don 't know me , but I know you .
I want to play a game .
Here 's what happens if you lose .
The device you 're wearing is hooked into your upper and lower jaws .
When the timer on the back goes off ,
your mouth will be permanently ripped open .
Think of it like a reverse bear trap .
Here , I 'll show you .
[ clock ticking ]
[ muffled screams ]
There 's only one key to open the device .
It 's in the stomach of your dead cellmate .
Look around , Amanda .
Know that I 'm not lying .
You better hurry up .
Live or die . Make your choice .
[ clock ticking ]
[ yelps ] No !
[ sniffles ]
And then I saw the body .
[ panting ]
[ clock ticking ]
[ electricity buzzing ]
There was a knife .
[ groaning ]
[ screaming ]
[ Sing ] He 'd been injected with an opiate overdose .
Couldn 't move or feel much of anything .
You mean ... he was alive ?
Was .
What happened after you took it off ?
[ screaming ]
[ sinister voice thorough puppet ] Congratulations . You are still alive .
Most people are so ungrateful to be alive , but not you .
Not anymore .
You are , in fact , a drug addict .
Isn 't that right , Mandy ?
Do you think that is why he picked you ?
[ crying ]
[ Tapp ] Are you grateful , Mandy ?
He ...
helped me .
[ light buzzing ]
Are you sure it 's him ?
Yeah , I 'm sure .
How do I know you 're telling the truth ?
You could be the one who put me in this room !
I 'm in exactly the same situation that you 're in .
Wrong . Wrong !
You 've got one thing I don 't ; information !
You know who did this .
Now , you either tell me what is really going on ,
or I 'll cut you with this ! You hear me ? I 'll cu - -
- What ? - It 's a two-way mirror .
[ man ] I can see you .
[ Adam ] 80 , that 's What this is ...
reality TV .
[ man ] Don 't look at me . I can 't help you .
Can you hear me in there , huh ?
I 'm having a blast .
This is the most fun I 've had without lubricant .
Make sure you 're getting everything .
That 's not gonna do anything .
You just want to leave it running on us ?
[ Lawrence ] Well , you won 't stop it .
Well , that 's why we can 't cut through these chains .
It 's why you won 't break that glass .
Every possible angle has been pre-thought out by him .
You make it sound like you admire this prick .
To overcome something ,
you have to understand what a perfect engine it is .
That 's how you fight disease .
Now the tape told us to find an " X. "
That " X " has to be somewhere in this room .
Help me find it .
How can you be the calm doctor guy when your wife and kid are out there ?
He 's got them , too .
He could be doing anything to them right now .
- Are you thinking about that ? - I am thinking about that .
I 've been thinking about the last thing I said to my daughter .
[ wind chimes ringing ]
[ wood banging softly ]
[ clock ticking ]
Diana , honey , are you OK ?
Diana , honey , can you hear me ?
Mommy .
What is it , sweet pea ?
There 's a man in my room .
Oh , honey , are you sure he 's not just hiding in your imagination ?
He talked to me .
[ sighs ] OK . I 'll come and check your room .
I want Daddy . He 'll get the scary man .
All right , if you want . Come on .
Larry , sorry to bother you , but your daughter had a bad dream again .
Just a minute .
She wants you to check her room .
Mm-hmm . Mm-hmm . Just-just got to finish this paragraph .
Come on , sweetie . I 'll check with you .
Nope . I 'm done .
See ? There 's no one in your room .
There 's no such thing as the bad man .
Now can you go to sleep ?
- I 'm still scared . - You are ?
Give me your tootsie .
[ grunts ]
Oh , what a big tootsie .
Remember this one ?
This little piggy went to market .
This little piggy stayed home .
This little piggy had roast beef .
This little piggy had none .
And this little piggy went ...
- Whee . .. all the way home ! - [ pager beeping ]
I hate that thing .
Well , I have to go to work , sweetheart .
You know what daddy 's job is like . Now , come on .
Let 's see .
Try and get some sleep now , OK ?
OK .
You 're not gonna leave us , are you , Daddy ?
What ?
What are you talking about ?
You mean leave you and Mommy ?
[ soft chuckle ] No . No , sweetheart . I ...
I would never do that .
Who gave you that idea ?
No one .
Well , it 's not true , OK ?
OK .
How much do I love you ?
- Love you very much . - ... very much .
- That 's right . That 's right . - [ laughs ]
- Good night , sweetie . - Good night , Daddy .
Tomorrow ...
I 'll read you your favorite story .
- OK . - OK .
[ Alison ] I don 't know how much longer I can do this , Larry .
[ Lawrence ] Do what ? What are you talking about ?
[ Alison ] How can you walk through life pretending that you 're happy ?
- I am happy . - That is complete bullshit .
I would rather you just break down and tell me that you hate me .
At least there would be some passion in it .
[ clock ticking ]
Would you like to see her ?
[ Adam ] She 's beautiful .
[ Lawrence ] Thank you .
You gonna have any more kids ?
Ah , we 've talked about it ,
but , uh ... with our schedules it 's ...
it 's difficult enough to concentrate on one .
So , where 's the lucky wife ?
There 's another picture behind the one you 're looking at .
It 's my favorite one because ...
we 're all in it together .
Someone , usually me , has to hold the camera ,
which means I 'm always missing from the photos .
[ sinister voice ] " X " marks the spot .
Sometimes you see more with your eyes shut .
It 's , uh ... it 's not here .
What ?
This photo you 're talking about is not here .
Really ? Are you sure ?
Yeah . Just ... Oh !
Why , he ... he must have taken it . I ...
[ Alison ] How can you walk through life pretending that you 're happy ?
- I am happy . - That is complete bullshit .
I 'd rather you break down and tell me that you hated me .
At least there would be some passion in it .
We 'll talk about this later , OK ?
[ siren blaring in distance ]
Just leave .
[ door creaks ]
[ panting ]
[ sinister voice ] Good night , little girl .
[ screams ]
Diana ?
[ gasps ]
[ screaming ]
Diana !
[ Diana crying , moaning ]
[ Alison panting ]
[ Alison muffled ]
Get away from her !
[ heartbeat ]
Mommy !
[ crying ]
[ heartbeat ]
[ heartbeat increasing ]
[ Alison muffled ]
Let go of her !
[ Tapp ] Oh , you little man , I see you .
Does Dr. Gordon know you 're at home with his wife ?
I know you know something .
What are you doing in there ?
Waiting for the doctor ?
I 'm waiting for the doctor , too .
I never should have let you go .
[ man screaming ]
[ woman ] There was someone standing outside here watching .
[ sinister voice ] I want to play a game .
[ man screaming ]
[ Tapp ] Jigsaw piece .
I think we 're gonna be here for a while , Sing .
Dr. Gordon , are you able to tell us where you were last night ?
And you have no idea how your penlight showed up at the murder scene ?
- We checked your alibi . It holds up . - Isn 't that right , Doctor ?
I never should have let you go .
Here we are .
That was , uh , quite an amazing story that poor woman told .
Look , I 'm ...
I 'm sorry I can 't be of more help to your investigation .
You know , we arrested a dentist last week .
He liked to play with kids a bit too much .
He lived two blocks from here .
The sewer lines run under this neighborhood , too ... Doctor .
[ engine starts ]
[ sinister voice ] Hello , Amanda . You don 't know me , but I know you .
I want to play a game .
Here 's what happens if you lose :
There 's a timer at the back of the device you 're wearing .
- [ man ] Hey . - When the timer goes off ...
[ indistinct chatter ]
[ videotape fast-forwarding ]
[ Sing ] Hey , I 'll catch you guys down there .
[ sinister voice ] Think of it like a reverse bear trap .
- I 'll show you . - [ clock ticking ]
- Hey , Tapp . - Hmm ?
We 're gonna go down to the grill to get a beer .
- You want to come ? - I don 't think so . Thanks anyway .
Well , you know , I always ask .
- There 's only one key to open ... - I 'll leave you to have fun up here .
- Mm-hm . - It 's in the stomach
of your dead cellmate .
Hey , Tapp , I don 't mean for this to be disrespectful .
Maybe you should find yourself a girlfriend .
[ both laugh softly ]
[ sinister voice ] It 's in the stomach of your dead Gel / mate .
Look around - -
Look around , Amanda . Know that I 'm not lying .
You better hurry up .
Wait , wait , wait . Hey , Sing .
- Get back here . - What ?
Mm !
[ sighs ]
What ?
Hey ...
Remember 118th street ?
Uh ... K2K .
That gang 's territory was only about four blocks .
Now listen to this .
[ alarm ringing faintly ]
We got to check the records for all the fire emergencies
that occurred in that area within the last two weeks .
Go , right now . Mmm !
[ Sing ] On the night of Tuesday the 17th ,
we got a fire alarm going off in the rear wing of 213 Stygian Street .
It 's an old listing . Used to be a mannequin factory .
You think we have enough for a warrant , though ?
Who said anything about a warrant ?
- Right now ? - Why not ?
Yeah , why not ?
[ gun being loaded ]
[ Tapp ] At least we 'll have the cover of darkness .
[ Sing ] Yeah . Well , so will anybody else .
[ banging ]
[ grunts ]
I got you .
What the hell is this ?
Oh , Shit .
[ groaning ]
[ Sing ] Oh , fuck !
[ muffled shouts ]
[ door opens ]
- Wait , Sing . - What ?
- Let 's see what he 's gonna do . - Why ? we fuckin ' got him .
- I just wanna make sure - - - What ?
We don 't know what he looks like . Let 's see what he 's gonna do .
- [ Sing ] No fucking way . - Sing !
- Fuck that . I 'm gonna take him . - Sing , Sing !
- [ muffled ] - What the fuck ? Shit !
[ muffled shouts continue ]
[ man ] Awake already , Jeff ?
I need more powerful tranquilizers next time .
Don 't cry . I 've given your life a purpose .
You 're a test subject for something greater than yourself .
- Freeze ! Police ! - Hold it right there ! Don 't move !
Put your fucking hands in the air !
[ drills whirring ]
[ man ] Now you 'll make a choice .
In 20 seconds , the life of this man will be ended .
- Shut it off and get down here ! - What 'd you do ? Turn it off !
- [ shouting ] - [ Tapp ] Sing , stop that thing .
- I 'm taking this bastard down . - Fine .
- Move ! - How do you turn it off ?
- Tell him how to stop it , asshole ! - One key will unlock it .
- Where is it ? - [ man ] It 's in the box .
Box ?
Fuck !
- Which key ? Which key ? - Tell him which key it is !
Time 's running out .
Shut up and get down here right now , asshole !
What 's more important to you , Officer ,
arresting me or the life of another human being ?
Get down on your knees , asshole !
Hands behind your head !
- [ Sing ] Tapp ! - Sick bastard !
Yes , I 'm sick , Officer .
Tapp , there 's like - - There 's 100 keys here !
Sick from the disease eating away at me inside ,
sick of people who don 't appreciate their blessings ,
sick of those who scoff at the suffering of others .
I 'm sick of it all !
Tapp !
No ! No ! Tapp ! Tapp ! Shit !
You 're OK . Let me see .
[ panting ]
- I 'm gonna be back . I 'm gonna be back . - OK .
Freeze , or I 'll shoot !
[ groaning ]
[ grunting ]
[ police radio chatter indistinct ]
I had you .
I had you on your knees .
But you 're running . You 're running .
You 're running scared because we had you .
We 're gonna close this case .
We - - We 're gonna close it . Right , Sing ? Right ?
We 're gonna close it , Sing .
[ Lawrence ] " X " marks the spot . " X " marks the spot .
We need to search this room again .
What are you doing over there ?
Excuse me .
Just because I 'm stuck in this room with you
doesn 't mean I have to report to you every ten seconds .
I really don 't see the point in us not helping one another .
What do you want me to do ? I 'm on a leash .
That 's exactly why we need to talk . We need to think .
I am thinking !
Then don 't keep me in the dark about what you 're thinking !
Turn off the lights .
What ?
Turn them off now , please .
Why ?
Just turn them off for a second .
Jesus . Behind you .
How come we didn 't see that before ?
The lights in here hadn 't charged it .
It must be glow-in-the-dark paint or something .
[ beeping ]
- Open it . - It 's locked .
The key , the one from my envelope , where is it ?
Where the fuck ? Here .
[ soft chuckle ]
A cell phone .
The most beautiful invention on this planet .
[ laughs ]
Make that second most beautiful invention .
- Give me that . - Are you joking ?
You 're gonna put something that you found in this room in your mouth ?
Yes . I 'm willing to risk it .
Give me that sweet cancer .
I don 't care . I really don 't .
Give me one of those .
[ sinister voice ] The cigarettes are harmless , I promise .
Smoking is only poisonous when it ends in bloodshed .
Think about this ; you don 't need a gun to kill Adam .
May I please have a cigarette ?
I 'm trying the police .
[ dialing ]
[ beeping ]
- [ beeping ] - Shit .
This was meant to receive calls , not make them .
Wait a minute .
This has happened before .
Last night , after I finished at the hospital ...
I was walking back to my car .
I thought I was alone , but ...
I 'm sure someone else was there .
[ camera clicks ]
[ busy signal ]
Great .
[ dialing ]
[ beeping ]
That ... thing was waiting for me .
How did you know to turn off the lights ?
Who cares ? It worked .
Yeah , but how did you know ?
- Instinct . - Instinct ?
Yeah .
You know what ? You 're a terrible liar .
You say that like you know me .
What else aren 't you telling me ?
[ scoffs ] Well , um , let 's see .
On my sixth birthday , my best friend at the time ,
Scott Tibbs , stabbed me with a rusty nail . I didn 't tell you about that .
I didn 't tell you that my last girlfriend ,
who was a feminist vegan punk ,
broke up with me because she thought I was too angry .
I haven 't told you that one of my toenails is slightly - -
Just stop it !
You knew to turn off these lights .
Whatever .
I 'm dealing with a juvenile .
- You want to know ? - Yeah !
Here it is .
Come .
Oh , God .
Wh-where did you get this ?
It was in your wallet ...
behind the photo of your daughter .
Wh-why didn 't you show me this before ?
I couldn 't .
[ whimpering ]
I 'm sorry .
What are you doing to them , you bastard ? !
OK . OK .
OK , I 've got to think now .
[ sinister voice ] Think about this .
You don 't need a gun to kill Adam .
When there 's that much poison in your blood ,
the only thing left to do is shoot yourself .
[ Adam ] What are you doing ?
Hey , what the hell are you doing ?
[ Lawrence whispering ] Shh . Adam , listen to me .
I want you to play along with me on this .
[ indistinct whispering ]
[ Lawrence ] You got that ?
So , you , uh ... you still want that cigarette ?
Um , yeah .
Sure .
[ lighter clatters ]
[ choking sounds ]
There ! I 've done it !
I 've killed him with the poison just like you wanted !
Now where 's my family ?
Where are they ?
- [ electrical buzzing ] - [ yelling ]
Jesus Christ !
- What are you - — - [ panting ]
- I-I just got electrocuted ! - What ?
Jesus , that was our way out .
Did you hear what I said ?
Get this thing off me ! Get it off !
Stop acting !
You think I would make that up
just to mess up your stupid fuckin ' Charade ? !
All right , that 's it .
[ grunting ]
Damn it !
[ panting ]
I remember everything now .
I remember how I got here .
[ music playing loudly on headphones ]
[ music stops ]
[ exhales ]
Ah ...
[ scoffs ]
Great .
[ door closes ]
[ door creaking ]
Is someone there ?
[ flash recharging ]
[ floorboards creaking ]
I can hear you .
[ flash recharging ]
[ floorboards creaking ]
- [ electronic laughter ] - [ gasps ]
What the .. . ?
What the fuck is that ?
- [ laughter stops ] - [ panting ]
What the .. . ?
- [ rattling ] - [ gasps ]
Who is that ?
Who 's in there ?
- [ creaking ] - Come out !
I 'll kill you , you motherfucker !
[ creaking ]
[ panting ]
[ yells ]
[ clock ticking ]
[ cell phone ringing ]
[ beep ]
Who is this ?
[ Diana on phone ] Daddy .
Diana .
Daddy , is that you ? [ crying ]
Yeah , baby , it 's me . I 'm here .
I 'm scared , Daddy .
Don 't worry , honey . Everything 's gonna be OK .
Where 's Mommy ?
She-she 's here with me .
Let me talk to her , sweetie . OK ? Put Mommy on .
The bad man from my room is here .
He has us tied up ...
and he has a gun .
Wh-what man ?
Please come home , Daddy .
Hello ? Hello ?
Diana ?
Diana !
Larry .
Ali ?
Is that you ?
Is Adam there ?
Well , how do you know ...
Ali ...
What is going on ?
Don 't believe Adam 's lies .
He knows you .
He knew all about you before today .
[ dial tone ]
Hello ? Ali ?
Ali ?
Hello !
God damn you !
If you so much as lay a finger on them , I 'll kill you !
You hear me , you son of a bitch ? ! I 'll kill you !
[ crying ]
Fuck !
Are they OK ?
My wife , she , uh ...
She mentioned your name .
What did she say ?
She told me ...
not to believe you .
Believe me about what ?
She told me you knew me .
Who are you ?
You know who I am .
Stop the lies ! You 're a liar !
I need to know the truth !
I 'm a liar ?
What did you do last night , Lawrence ?
Work at a hospital , saving sick children ?
You told me that after you left your house last night ,
you went to work at a hospital .
That 's because it 's the truth .
No , it 's not .
Your wife is right , Larry .
You don 't recall getting your picture taken in that parking lot ?
I can prove that you didn 't go anywhere near a hospital last night .
It 's not the first time I 've done it , either , Larry .
I 've been taking pictures of you for a few days now .
- Why ? - You want to know what I do ?
I get paid to take pictures of rich guys like you
who go to seedy , out-of — the-way motels to fuck their secretaries .
Last night , I went to your house and watched you leave .
I followed you ...
all the way to that shit-bag hotel .
You 've , uh , had these with you the whole time ?
No , I found them in there with the hacksaws .
I don 't know how they got there .
Yeah , right . You 're so full of it !
Ah , face it , Larry . We 're both bullshitters .
But my camera isn 't . It doesn 't know how to lie .
It only shows you what 's put right in front of it .
Just out of curiosity , what did you do in that motel room ?
You got out of there pretty fast .
Why did you , um ...
deem it necessary to page me when you knew I was at home ?
I didn 't know if you were gonna make it .
But I-I gave you a precise time at which to page me .
You-you can 't do that .
It 's not like I know the rules for this sort of stuff .
[ baby crying in other room ]
What 's wrong , Dr. Gordon ?
Look , urn ...
it was wrong of me to make you come here .
- But I thought we - - - No , no . Please .
I 'm sorry .
[ phone ringing ]
You tell anyone you were here ?
No .
[ ringing continues ]
Hello .
It 's for you .
For me ?
Hello .
[ man whispering on phone ] [ know What you 're doing , Doctor .
I — —
[ dial tone ]
[ hangs up telephone ]
- I have to go . - What happened ?
I got to go .
[ sighs ]
[ camera clicks ]
Who was it ?
Who was what ?
The person who paid you to follow me , who was it ?
He calls himself Bob , and he gives me the money up front .
Two-hundred bucks a night .
If I 'd known I was gonna end up here ,
I would have asked for a hell of a lot more .
What-what does that mean ?
Does that mean you saw what happened to me ?
What I saw was you get into your car . That 's it .
I didn 't ask your name . I didn 't know who you were .
I don 't know how I got here . I don 't know how you got here .
I just took the shots and went straight home to develop them .
Next thing I know , I 'm chained to a pipe in some prehistoric bathroom ,
staring at the guy I 've been taking shots of all night .
Clearly , whoever paid you to take pictures of me
- is the one who put us here . - Maybe .
What do you mean " maybe " ? Of course it is . What did he look like ?
- I don 't know , he 's just a guy . - Was he tall ? Was he skinny , obese , what ?
I don 't take notes about his appearance .
- You must remember something about him . - I can 't !
You 're telling me you don 't remember a thing about the guy ?
- I told you - - - Oh , for fuck 's sake ! I give up !
He 's a tall black guy . He 's got a scar around his neck , OK ?
Tapp .
Detective Tapp .
[ Adam ] Whoa .
The guy who paid me to take these photos was not a cop .
No , no , no . He was - - He was discharged from the police force .
He broke down after his partner was killed .
But that didn 't stop him from harassing me .
The guy became obsessed .
He convinced himself that I must have somehow been involved with the murders .
- I mean - - He 's crazy . - [ laughing ]
And you helped him .
You took money from him to invade my privacy .
- How could you do that ? - Call it my need to eat .
Right . Right . You know what , Adam ?
You 're not a victim of this game ; you 're part of it .
Oh , really ? Obviously , this cop thinks you 're the one behind it all .
I told you , he 's not a cop .
He 's a bottom feeder , just like you .
What are you more pissed off about : the fact that I took some shots of you ,
or the fact that I took some shots of you while you were cheating on your wife ?
I did not cheat on her !
What do you care what I think anyway ?
I don 't give a crap if you covered yourself in peanut butter
and had a 15-hooker gang bang .
How did I get here ?
I - - I had everything in order .
My whole life was in perfect order .
[ Alison sniffles ]
[ crying ]
[ door closes ]
[ spits ]
Sweetheart , are you OK ?
Mommy just needs you to be
really , really , really , really strong right now .
I 'm not gonna let anybody hurt you .
You got that ?
OK . That 's my good girl .
[ Adam ] Hey , was there someone else at your house last night ,
besides your wife and daughter ?
[ Lawrence ] No .
[ Adam ] Well , there 's someone here .
[ static buzzes ]
[ Lawrence ] I know him .
Zep .
[ Adam ] Who ?
His name is Zep .
He 's an orderly at my hospital .
Zep . You perverted little psychopath .
I 'm gonna take great pleasure in seeing you pay for this ,
you bastard fuck !
Look .
We 're out of time .
Shh , shh , shh . Sweetie , sweetie , sweetie .
- Mommy , help me ! - Shh ...
Dr. Gordon 's time is up .
Now I 've got to do what I 've got to do ,
and I 'm afraid it has to be you that tells him he failed .
[ cell phone rings ]
Is that you , Zep , you bastard ? !
I know it 's you , you son of a bitch !
[ Alison over phone ] L-Larry .
Ali ?
You failed .
[ grunting ]
Hello ?
Wait .
[ panting ]
Don 't move ! Stay on the ground .
Give me - - Give me the phone .
Give it to me !
- Larry . - Ali .
Honey , are you all right ?
No . No - - No , we 're not .
Get down !
Larry , where are you ?
I don 't know .
I 'm being held captive in a room somewhere .
What-what are you talking about ?
- [ Lawrence ] I 'm so sorry , Ali . - Honey , we need you here .
I 'm so sorry for everything . It 's my fault .
Please forgive me .
I 've always been happy with you .
Mommy . [ cries ]
- [ grunts ] - [ screaming ]
Jesus !
[ screaming ]
Ali !
[ gunshot ]
[ screaming ]
Ali ! Ali !
Mommy , help me !
[ yells ]
Freeze !
[ screams ]
[ gunshots and screaming over phone ]
[ sobbing ]
- What ? - Oh , no .
- [ gun clicking ] - What the fuck ?
[ yelling ]
- [ grunting ] - [ panting ]
[ sobbing ]
Mrs. Gordon ?
Diana !
I 'm gonna kill your husband now , Mrs. Gordon .
[ grunting ]
[ yelling ]
[ sobbing ]
[ electrical buzzing ]
Lawrence !
Lawrence , get up !
Get up !
I need you !
Oh , thank God .
I thought you were dead .
[ groaning ]
He-he ... he electrocuted me .
I-I told you . The same thing happened to me .
See ? I wasn 't lying . See ?
Fuck this shit !
[ tires screeching ]
[ grunting ]
[ cell phone ringing ]
[ groaning ]
[ ringing ]
[ grunting ]
[ man hole cover slides open ]
- [ ringing continues ] - No !
[ crying ]
Lawrence , calm down .
There must be a way out of this .
Oh , shut up ! Just shut up !
My family needs me !
[ sobbing ]
No ! God !
God ! No !
[ screaming ]
Lawrence ! I have a family , too !
I don 't see them ! That 's my mistake ! It 's a mistake I 'd like to fix !
[ Tapp ] I 'm gonna kill you , you sick asshole !
- [ screaming ] - [ ringing continues ]
Lawrence ! Stop it .
[ grunting ]
Lawrence , just calm down .
There 's a way out of here .
There 's a way out !
Lawrence !
No ! What - - No ! Oh , my God !
What are you doing ?
[ both screaming ]
[ grunting ]
[ screaming ]
- [ screaming ] - [ sobbing ]
[ gasps ]
What ... are you doing ?
What are you ... what are you ...
Oh , my God ! Oh , my God !
Lawrence , don 't ! No ! No , Lawrence , please !
I 'm begging you !
Lawrence ! It 's not me who did this to you !
[ gun cocks ]
You have to die .
No ! I want to live !
- I want to live ! - I 'm sorry .
- I want to live ! - My family .
[ yells ]
[ crying ]
There !
I 've done it !
Now show them to me !
Show them to me .
[ man ] Thank you very much , Officer .
- [ Alison ] Larry ? - Did you get through to him ?
- No . There 's still no answer . - It 's all right . I 've called the police .
Everything is OK .
[ indistinct chatter ]
[ loud banging ]
You bastard !
I 'll fucking kill you ! I 'll fucking kill you !
You fucking bastard ! I 'll fucking kill you !
- [ gun clicking ] - I 'll fucking kill you .
[ breathing heavily ]
You 're too late .
Why ?
It 's the rules .
[ yells ]
[ gunshot ]
[ flesh smashing ]
[ groans ]
[ yells ]
You 're gonna be all right .
You 're just wounded-wounded in the shoulder .
I have to go and get help .
Don 't leave me !
No ! No ! No !
No !
[ yells ]
Lawrence !
Don 't-don 't worry .
I 'll bring someone back .
I promise .
OK .
Key . Key .
[ sinister voice ] Hello , Mr. Hindle ...
or as they called you around the hospital ... Zep .
I want you to make a choice .
[ Diana screaming ]
There 's a slow-acting poison coursing through your system
which only I have the antidote for .
Will you murder a mother and her child to save yourself ?
Dr. Gordon 's time is up .
Mrs. Gordon !
[ sinister voice ] Listen carefully if you will .
There are rules .
Why ?
It 's the rules .
[ sinister voice ] The key to that chain is in the bathtub .
He 's a very interesting person . His name is John .
He has an inoperable frontal-lobe tumor .
[ sinister voice ] I 'm sick from the disease eating away at me inside .
Looks like our friend Jigsaw .
[ sinister voice ] I 'm sick of people Who don 't appreciate their blessings .
It looks like our guy likes to book himself
front-row seats for his own sicko games .
[ sinister voice ] Hello , Mark , Paul , Amanda , Zep , Adam , Dr. Gordon .
I want to play a game .
[ yells ]
[ electrical buzzing ]
[ yelling ]
[ gasping ]
[ sinister voice ] Most people are so ungrateful to be alive ...
but not you , not anymore .
[ screaming ]
Game over .
[ Adam screaming ]
Don 't ! Don 't !
Don 't !
[ screaming ]
[ screaming fades ]